

Nashville, TN
423-737-8119
whitneym92@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/whitney-monk/
qithub.com/whitneym92

# WHITNEY MONK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

I am a software developer with a background in Business Management. My restaurant experience has allowed me to apply skills such as leadership, time management, problem solving, multi-tasking, collaboration and customer satisfaction to my new found love for software development.

### SKILLS

HTML5 Git CSS3 Github JavaScript MySQL **jQuery j**Axios Node.js React.js **Bootstrap** MongoDB Handlebars.js **Express APIs** Media Queries **JSON AJAX** 

# PROJECT EXPERIENCE

# **Recipe Hub**

- An application for busy individuals that allows a user to search for a recipe by entering ingredients that they have on hand.
- Built with Bumla, CSS, HTML, jQuery, Javascript and two API's.
- github.com/dbreznay/Recipe-Hub

### **Popcorn Bucket List**

- An application that allows a movie lover to search and save movies to a watchlist.
- Built with Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, Node.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Express and Passport.js.
- github.com/demi0504/brutal-butterflies

# CAREER SUMMARY

# **Mayday Brewery**

Murfreesboro, TN, June 2020-Present

- Bartender
  - Produce and balance daily sales reports to assess and coordinate staff, while subsequently improving organizational profit.
  - Demonstrates the ability to multi-task at a face pace while dealing with various situations/individuals with over 1,000 customers weekly

#### Demos'

Murfreesboro, TN, September 2019- June 2020

Server

# **Cootie Browns**

Johnson City, TN, July 2008-September 2019

- Manager
  - Increased sales 25% yearly via quality control programs
  - Maintained expenses to stay below the monthly budget
  - Recruited, hired, supervised, scheduled and motivated staff of over 50 employees
- Shift Leader/ Server
  - Cultivated strong business relationships with customers to build business development
  - Built a cohesive top-performing team via an extensive training program

# **EDUCATION**

# Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN, 2020

**Boot Camp Certificate** 

 Intensive 24-week boot camp for JavaScript Full Stack Web Development

# East Tennessee State University, Johnson City, TN, December 2014

Bachelor of Business Administration

 Accreditation: Association to Advance Collegiate Schools of Business